어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri Martial Artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예자 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri Martial Artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi enters-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!
시시한 일로 싸운 무사시, 코지로, 센히메.
Musashi, Kojirō, and Senhime have fought over an insignificant thing.
무사시는 사이고를 쫒아다니고, 센히메는 시라누이를 정탐하고, 코지로는 치한으로 잡힌다.
Musashi chased Saigo, Senhime spied on Shiranui, and Kojirō was caught as a pervert.
사이고를 시라누이의 동료로 착각한 무사시는 천공환으로 달려들지만, 아니, 그 곳엔 료마 씨가!
Musashi misjudged Saigo as on Shiranui's side and slashed at Saigo, but there was Mr. Ryoma with him!
시라누이에게 잡힌 코지로와 센히메를 구하러 간 무사시.
Musashi went to rescue Kojirō and Senhime captured by Shiranui.
싸움 후 일단 셋은 화해하고 규슈를 향해 갔다.
After the battle, those three made up, and went to Kyushu.
나
비뚤어지오
I
Become Delinquent
-사츠마니아이오.
-응.
-That must be Satsumania-dasu.
-Yeah.
드디어 시라누이 일족이 있는 사츠마니아에 진입한 무사시, 코지로, 센히메였다.
Musashi, Kojirō, and Senhime finally entered Satsumania where Shiranui Clan is.
여기가 사츠마니아이오.
So this is Satsumania-dasu!
(桜島, 사쿠라지마 섬: 가고시마 현에 있는 화산섬)
(桜島, Sakurajima: lit. Cherry Blossom Island. A volcanic island at Kagoshima Prefecture.)
저게 사쿠라지마 섬이오!
And that must be Sakurajima-dasu!
웅장하네.
That's a magnificent!
사츠마니아는 저 사쿠라지마 섬처럼 불타고 있소이다.
Satsumania is burning just like that Sakurajima-gowasu.
그럼.
Then.
나중에 꼭 놀러 갈게!
We'll see you later to play!
기쁘게 기다리겠다.
Then I'll wait for that.
조만간 다시 봅시다.
See you soon.
사이고 씨도 건강히!
See you, Mr. Saigo!
그래.
Thanks.
저질러 버렸소?
Did he do it-dasu?
괜찮아, 괜찮아! 변소면 아무렴 어떠냐!
It's alright, if it's a toilet to him or not!
-정말 도량이 큰 인물이오.
-그러게...
-He's really generous-dasu!
-Agreed...
드디어 시라누이 일족의 본거지에 왔어.
We're finally at the habitat of Shiranui Clan.
방심해선 안 돼.
Do not let your guards down.
정말 예쁜 사람이오!
She's really pretty-dasu!
뭣이오, 갑자기?!
What was that for-dasu?!
방심하지 말랬지!
I just told you to not to let your guards down!
아, 알고 있소!
I- I know that-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
그, 그렇게 큰 소리 내면 안 되오! 여긴 시라누이 일족의 본거지이오.
Y- you must not yell loudly here-dasu! We're at the habitat of Shiranui Clan-dasu!
뭐야, 지금와서 잘난 척은.
Oh, you're saying that now?
어, 뭣이오?
Hey, what's that-dasu?
사츠마니아 명물: 사츠마아게
Satsumania Specialty: Satsumaage
자, 자, 도전할 사람 없습니까!
Is anybody up for a challenge?
이 사츠마아게를 500개 먹으면 무료요!
If you manage to eat 500 Satsumaages, then it's free!
사츠마아게?!
Satsumaage?!
나, 도전하오!
I'll do it-dasu!
안 하쇼?
Are you not going to do it?
아야야야야야야! 뭔 짓이오!
Ouch! What are you doing?!
무사시!
Musashi!
뭣이오! 타인의 낙을 방해하는 자는 개한테 차여 죽소!
What was that for-dasu?! Whoever interferes with someone else's pleasure will die from being kicked by a dog-dasu!
아직도 안 질렸냐!
Didn't you learn your lesson?!
시나가와에서 단고 먹기에 도전해서 막 혼난 참이잖아!
Did you forget that you were scolded because you participated in dango eating contest in Shinagawa just before?!
그, 그런 소릴 해도 내 배가...
N- no matter what you say, my stomach is empty...
정말 그래도 제일의 무예가를 노리는 무사냐!
Are you serious that you want to be the best martial artist?!
뭔 소리를 해도, 속담에 이런 게 있소! 배가 고파선 싸울 수 없다고!
Again, no matter what you say, there is a proverb-dasu! You can't fight when you're hungry!
이런 속담도 있다! 무사는 굶어도 배부른 척 한다고!
There also is a proverb! A swordsman has a full stomach even when he's starving!
어? 무사는 굶으면 볼일을 안 보오?
What? A swordsman won't defecate when he's starving-dasu?
아니, 아니, 아니! 이제 됐다! 그 근성 내가 여기서 바로잡아 주겠다!
Wrong, wrong, wrong! Forget it! I'll fix your rotten attitude right here!
해 보잔 것이오?!
Up for a fight-dasu?!
잠깐, 코지로.
Stop, Kojirō.
무사시. 네가 제일 나빠!
Musashi. You are the worst!
센짱...
Sen-chan...
왜 그렇게 주접스러운 거야?
Why are you so gluttonous?
단지 사츠마아게를 500개를 공짜로 먹을 수 있다니 경제적이라는 이유에서...
It's only because it is economical to eat 500 Satsumaages for free...
무사시가 나빴네!
Musashi's wrong!
주접스러워!
Gluttonous!
그, 그런! 내게 먹지 말라니...
N- no way! You can't ask me not to eat!
징징대봤자 소용없어.
Sobbing won't persuade us.
센짱까지 그런 소리를 하다니...
Sen-chan, did you really say that?
나... 나...
I... I...
나 비뚤어지겠소!
I'll turn delinquent-dasu!
무, 무사시!
M- Musashi!
비뚤어지오! 사츠마아게 먹고 싶었소! 비뚤어지오! 비뚤어지오...
I'll become bad-dasu! I wanted to eat Satsumaage-dasu! I'll be delinquent-dasu!
완전 얘라니까.
He's such a brat.
비뚤어지오, 비뚤어지오, 더 비뚤어지오...
I'll be bad-dasu, I'll be even more delinquent-dasu...
위험했소.
That was close-dasu.
혹시...
Are you...
(아사노 요코: 아사노 유코로 추정.)
(Asano Youko: seems to mean Asano Yuko)
그렇게 무사시가 뒤돌아보자 거기에는 클레오파트라인가 요녀인가, 혹은 아사노 요코같은 미녀가.
And when Musashi turned back... is she Cleopatra, a siren, or a beautiful woman like Asano Youko?
사츠마니아의 여성은 눈부시게 아름답소...
All the women from Satsumania are gorgeous-dasu...
당신의 이름은?
What's your name?
아, 나, 무사시라 하오. 볼 일 있소?
My name is Musashi-dasu. Do you have anything to talk to me-dasu?
꽤 솜씨가 능숙한 사람이라 보고 판단하였습니다만.
You seem to be very fluent in using swords.
아니, 그 정도는 아니오.
I wouldn't say that much-dasu!
아니아니, 겸손이라니. 만약 괜찮다면 이 앞의 찻집에서 이야기라도.
No need to be humble. Would you want to talk with me at a teahouse nearby?
아, 그래도 누나는 어떤 사람이오?
But who are you, sister?
누나라. 누나가 아닙니다. 제 이름은 히미코.
Sister. I am not a sister. My name is Himiko.
(히미코: 왜의 여왕, 서기 170-248년)
(Himiko: Queen of Wa (ancient Japan), 170–248 AD)
히미코
Himiko
히미코?
Himiko?
어때요. 일만 냥 무예 대회에 출전해 보는 건.
Would you like to join Ten Thousand Ryo Martial Arts Competition?
일만 냥 무예 대회?
Ten Thousand Ryo Martial Arts Competition?
이건 규슈 제일의 무예 대회로 전국에서 실력에 자신이 있는 카라쿠리 무예가가 모여 와요.
That is the most recognized martial arts competition in Kyushu,
where Karakuri martial artists with confidence in themselves gather from the whole country.
헤, 그렇게 대단하오!
Is it really that awesome-dasu?!
네. 주최하고 있는 분께서 부탁받았어요. 강한 무예가가 있으면 꼭 부르라고.
Yes. I've been asked by the host, to invite whoever martial artist that looks strong.
무사시 님, 어떠세요?
Mr. Musashi, would you like to join?
그렇게 말하자면 무예가 제일을 노리는 나로서는 꼭 나가고 싶소!
Since you've said that, I definitely want to join, since I want to be the best martial artist-dasu!
아직 충분히 못 먹어서 힘이 안 나오.
I can't show all my powers yet since I didn't eat enough yet-dasu.
그거라면 안심을. 대회 출전자에게는 빠짐없이 힘의 근원, 돼-
Don't worry about that. To all the participants, they'll be provided with pi-
돼지 통구이이오?
Is it a pig whole roast-dasu?
아니요, 돼지 네모조림입니다.
No, it's a cubed pig meat stew.
굳이 사각형으로 안 하고 통구이여도 괜찮은데...
It doesn't have to be rectangle - no need for cubed meat stew-dasu...
출전하시는 거죠?
Are you participating?
그렇소!
That's right-dasu!
히미코 씨 상냥하고 마치 엄마 같소!
Ms. Himiko is so kind that she's as if my mother-dasu!
왜 그러세요? 제 얼굴에 뭐라도?
What's wrong? Is there something on my face?
아, 아무것도 아니오.
I- it's nothing-dasu.
돼지 네모조림이라는게 이 것이었소! 정말 맛있소!
So this is the cubed meat stew-dasu! It's so good-dasu!
그럼 편히 쉬세요.
Take your time.
어, 히미코 씨, 보러 안 가오?
Ms. Himiko, aren't you going to watch-dasu?
네, 저는 안내하는 역할입니다. 승리를 기원하겠습니다.
Yes, I am working for guidance. I'm wishing for your victory.
저, 히미코 씨, 하나 질문이 있소.
Uh, Ms. Himiko, I have one question-dasu.
뭔가요?
What is it?
마음대로 더 먹어도 되오?
Can I have unlimited dishes-dasu?
만족할 때까지 즐기세요.
As long as you're not satisfied yet!
이야, 그걸 들으니 안심이오!
That made me relived-dasu!
이렇게 맛있는 것도 그냥 먹게 해주고 무예 대회에도 출전할 수 있게 해 주고...
She let me eat such a nice food for free, and let me participate in a martial arts competition...
미인이고, 히미코 씨, 좋은 사람이오!
Ms. Himiko is one beautiful and good person-dasu!
먹히는군, 먹혀!
It's working, it's working!
히미코 님, 일만 냥 무예 대회 준비가 되었습니다.
Lord Himiko, Ten Thousand Martial Arts Competition is now ready.
좋다. 무예가는 모여 있는 것 같군.
Good. It seems that the martial artists are gathered.
예. 실력에 자신이 있는 누구에게도 뒤지지 않는 용사들입니다.
Yessir. They are warriors that are equally competent.
쿠로다
Kuroda
좋다. 여기서 살아 남은 자가 부하가 되어 일해 주겠지. 우리 시라누이 일족을 향해.
Great. Whoever survived this will become our subordinate and work for us, for Shiranui Clan.
예.
Yessir.
그 때야말로 지팡구는 이에야스 대신 시라누이 일족의 손에.
When that happens. instead of Ieyasu, Shiranui Clan will rule over Jipangu.
그리고 히미코 님은 지팡구의 지배자가 됩니다.
And Lord Himiko will become the ruler of Jipangu.
그렇지.
You're right.
일만 냥 무예 대회
Ten Thousand Ryo Martial Arts Competition
지금부터 일먄 냥 무예 대회를 시작한다.
We will begin Ten Thousand Ryo Martial Arts Competition soon.
슬슬이오.
Finally-dasu.
시작!
Begin!
남부류 류인손!
Nanbu style Ryuinson!
후겐류 사쿠라지마도캉!
Fugen style Sakurajimadokan!
어라? 진검이오.
What the-?! They're using real swords-dasu!
너 몰랐냐? 일만 냥 무예 대회는 진검으로 승부해.
Didn't you know that this competition is done with real swords?
여기서 살아남은 자가 시라누의 일족을 위해 정말로 쓸 수 있는 무예가가 될 것이다.
Whoever survives this will be the martial artist who will actually be helpful to Shiranui Clan.
이, 이건 안 좋소.
T- this is bad-dasu.
무슨 일입니까.
What's wrong?
아, 아니, 설마 진검으로 승부할 줄은.
T- that's... I didn't know this was a real sword match.
설마 달아갈 생각? 이 무예 대회, 한번 참가한 이상 계속 이기는 수밖에 살아남을 길은 없다.
Are you trying to run away? Once you've joined this competition, your only hope of being alive is to keep winning.
과연 무사시의 운명은 어떻게! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
How will Musashi end up? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
by Subdivers
어이, 무사시!
Hey, Musashi!
무사시! 무사시! 나와!
Musashi! Musashi! Show yourself!
대체 어디에 간 거야?
Where did he disappear to?!
나, 너무 지나친 말을 했나 봐.
Maybe I went too far on him.
그런 걸로 화내는 무사시가 나쁜 겁니다. 그런 놈은 냅두고 여관에서 쉽시다.
It's Musashi's fault for being angry because of that. Leave that guy alone and let's take some rest in an inn.
그래도 삐뚤어지겠다니, 어째. 무사시가 불량해지기라도 하면.
But he told us he'll become deliquent. What if Musashi actually becomes so?
어이어이어이, 내 앞에서 꺼지시오.
Heyheyhey, get out of my way-dasu.
불량해지는 제일의 이유는 주변 사람에게 이해받지 못한 소외감이라고, 전에 읽은 잡지에 적혀 있었어.
It was written on the magazine I read before
that the primary reason for becoming delinquent is not being understood by people around.
그런 식욕을 어떻게 이해하란 겁니까! 게다가 삐뚤어져 봤자 얼마나 그러겠어요.
How can I understand appetite like that?! Also, he wouldn't be really delinquent even if he try so hard.
코지로. 부탁이야. 왠지 걱정돼. 어떻게든 무사시를 찾아 줘.
Kojirō. Please. I'm worried about him. Find Musashi for me.
센히메 님의 부탁이라면...
If it's you who're asking me, Senhime...
이천일류 무사시이오.
I am Musashi of Niten'ichiryu-dasu.
어, 벤케이 씨!
Mr. Benkei!
설마 무사시하고 하게 될 거라고는 생각도 못 했다. 이것도 수련의 일부인가 보지.
I never thought I'm going to face you here, Musashi. This must be a part of my training.
벤케이 씨, 정말 진검으로 하오?
Mr. Benkei, are we really doing this with real swords?
그게 일만 냥 무예 대회. 진검으로 싸우는 이 대회야말로 진짜 용사를 가르는 대회다!
That is how this competition is. This competition will find out the true warrior, with real swords!
진심을 다해 싸워라!
Fight earnestly!
어쩔 수 없소...
It can't be helped-dasu...
무사시! 잠시 안 본 사이 실력을 올렸구나!
Musashi! You got better meanwhile!
이기는 것뿐만이 아니라 수련도 하고 있었소!
Not only I kept winning, but I kept training-dasu!
좋은 마음가짐이다!
Good mindset!
당했다!
Damn!
잡았다!
I got you!
순진하군, 무사시! 진검 승부에 정이란 없다!
You're naive, Musashi! There is no mercy in a real sword match!
내, 내가 졌소. 벤케이 씨, 베어 주시오.
I- I lost-dasu. Mr. Benkei, cut me off-dasu.
아니, 아무리 나라고 해도 친구를 벨 수는 없다.
No. Even for me, it is impossible to cut off a friend.
뭘 하나, 벤케이! 무사시를 죽여라!
What are you doing, Benkei? Kill Musashi!
승부가 났으니 이미 됐잖나!
The match is settled, so that's it!
이 무예 대회는 상대를 죽이지 않으면 승리로 인정되지 않는다.
In this competition, a match is not set until one is killed.
그럴 수는 없다!
I will not kill him!
그럼 둘 다 죽어라!
Then you two must die together!
뭐, 뭣이오?!
W- what is this-dasu?!
구워져 죽어라.
Be roasted to death.
멈춰라!
Stop!
누구냐!
Who's there?!
나는 우시와카. 우시와카라 하오!
I am Ushiwaka. You may call me Ushiwaka.
-우시와카 씨!
-우시와카 님!
-Mr. Ushiwaka!
-Ushiwaka!
다시는 속으면 안 됩니다. 이 일만 냥 무예 대회는 시라누이 일족의 음모입니다.
You must not be fooled again. This Ten Thousand Ryo Martial Arts Competition is a plot of Shiranui Clan.
뭐, 뭣이오?!
W- what did you say?!
-뭐, 뭐야?
-사실이냐!
-W- what?!
-Are you serious?!
무슨 희롱을!
What kind of nonsense is that?!
이래도냐!
Look at this!
일만 냥 무예 대회는 수상하다고 생각해서,
I assumed that this martial arts competition was suspicious,
여기저기 알아보니 배후에 조종하는 놈이.
and when I looked for the truth here and there, there was someone pulling strings.
주변을 망보고 있던 이 자가 전부 말해 주었다!
This guy standing guard told me everything!
너무하오! 검의 수련에 명을 거는 무예가를 속이다니!
That's deplorable-dasu! How dare you fool the martial artists who risk their lives for the training of swords-dasu?!
-그래, 그래!
-업신여기지 마라!
-Yeah, yeah!
-Don't look down of us!
칫, 겨우 연 무예 대회를.
Tch. How dare he do that to my competition.
그래, 이런 것에 생명을 거는 것은 멍청한 짓이다.
Yes. Risking lives for this is foolish.
에잇, 시끄럽다! 다들 나와라!
Silence! Everyone, show up!
무사시, 되는 대로 해라!
Musashi, do whatever you can!
알겠소!
Got it-dasu!
우릴 속였겠소!
You fooled us-dasu!
무사시, 네게는 내가 상대해 주겠다!
Musashi, I will face you!
이 자식! 잡아 주겠소!
You bastard! I'll get you-dasu!
비, 비겁한!
H- how cowardly!
헷, 진검승부라는 것은 이런 것이오!
Heh! This is what a real sword fight is-dasu!
그렇지. 이건 네가 맞다.
That's right. You were right this time.
그러면 긴장을 늦추지 않겠다!
Then I will not lose focus!
이천일류 철풍차!
Nitenichiryu: Iron Windmill!
웃기는군! 이렇게 된 바 비장의 수를!
How foolish! Time to show my ultimate move!
시라누이 인법, 화염술!
Shiranui Ninja Technique, Flame Technique!
젠장!
Damn!
이천일류, 회오리검!
Nitenichiryu: Tornado Sword!
무사시! 그만하지 못할까!
Musashi! Halt!
저런. 건물 전체에 불이 붙었다!
This is bad! There is fire all over the building!
히미코 님, 에도토피아에서 손님이.
Lord Himiko, there is a visitor from Edotopia.
슬슬 기다리는 사람이 왔군요.
The person I've been waiting for is finally here.
한조 님, 환영합니다.
Welcome. Mr. Hanzo.
히미코 님도 점점 아름다워지시는군요.
Ms. Himiko, you're getting even more beautiful every time.
그건 감사합니다.
Thank you.
이야, 규슈는 정말 따뜻하군요.
Kyushu is really warm.
항상 그렇지요.
You are right.
하마터면 타죽을 뻔했다!
You almost roasted us to death!
미안하오. 그새 신나 버려서...
I'm sorry-dasu. I got so excited-dasu...
그래도 살아서 다행이오.
Anyway we live, and that's great-dasu.
벤케이, 왜 이런 무식한 짓을 했나.
Benkei, why did you do such a foolish act?
우시와카 님! 용서해 주쇼! 무예 대회에 대한 소식을 듣고 그저 참가하고 말았습니다!
Ushiwaka, please forgive me! I heard about the martial arts competition and I just joined in!
수련이 부족하다!
You lack discipline!
이제 됐소, 우시와카 씨.
It's alright now, Mr. Ushiwaka.
아무래도 벤케이가 피해를 입힌 것 같으니, 미안하다.
It seems that Benkei troubled you. I apologize for that.
아니아니, 나하고 벤케이 씨는 속았었소.
No, no, Mr. Benkei and I were being deceived.
덕분에 살았소, 우시와카 씨.
You saved me, Mr. Ushiwaka.
언젠가 다시 보자. 가자, 벤케이!
See you again someday. Let's go, Benkei!
예!
Yessir!
잘 지내시오!
See you!
무사시!
Musashi!
코지로!
Kojirō!
정말, 어디 갔었냐!
Really... where did you go to?!
응, 히미코 씨라는 완전 친절한 사람에게!
A kind person named Ms. Himiko took me!
히미코 씨?
Ms. Himiko?
그렇소. 그렇게 보니 히미코 씨도 속고 있었소. 그런 사람을 속이다니...
I see. Ms. Himiko was being deceived, too. To deceive someone like her...
시라누이 일족도 나쁜 짓만 골라 하오.
Shiranui Clan does all the bad things.
음, 어쨌든 센히메 님이 걱정하고 계신다. 어서 돌아가자.
Well... Anyway, Senhime is really worried about you. Let's go back.
알겠소!
Got it-dasu!
바보바보바보바보바보바보바보바보바보바보바보!
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot!
-미안하오!
-I'm sorry-dasu!
정말, 어디 갔던 거야?
Where did you really go to?!
미안하오!
I'm sorry-dasu!
나, 무사시가 돌아오면...
I was thinking that, when you come back, Musashi...
배가 가득 차도록 먹게 해 주어야지 하고 생각해서 계속 기다렸는데!
I will let you eat as much as you want, and I've been waiting for you!
아, 사츠마아게이오!
Hey, those are Satsumaages-dasu!
정말, 무사시 따위 몰라!
You're so bad, Musashi!
몰라몰라몰라몰라몰라몰라몰라몰라!
Bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad, bad!
-내가 잘못했소! 정말 미안하오! 용서해 주시오!
-It's my fault-dasu! I'm really sorry-dasu! Forgive me-dasu!
정말 반성은 하고 있냐?
Do you even know that you deserve this?
반성하고 있소.
I know-dasu!
게걸스럽기만 한 무사시는 어쩔 수가 없다.
Musashi's gluttony cannot be fixed.
우시와카의 활약으로 위기는 넘겼지만, 한조가 끼어든 시라누이 일족의 음모는 계속된다.
The crisis has been passed through, but Shiranui Clan's plot thickens as Hanzo joins.
과연 무사시 일행 앞에는 뭐가 기다리고 있는가?
What is waiting for Musashi's group?
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't worry too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep going! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
먹을 것에 약한 나는 시라누이 일족의 함정에 빠져 독이 들어간 음식을 먹어버리고 마비되오.
Because I am weak for foods, I fall into the trap of Shiranui Clan by eating poisonous foods and gets paralyzed-dasu.
그 동안 코지로는 소중한 칼이 부러지고 마오.
Meanwhile, Kojirō's precious sword has been broken-dasu.
완전히 침울해져 버렸소.
He got totally depressed-dasu.
모노호시자오를 대신할 긴 칼을 찾고 있으나 어디에도 없소!
I looked for a sword that will replace Monohoshizao, but it's nowhere to be found-dasu!
다음 이야기! 어?! 침울한 코지로이오!
Next story! Huh?! Depressed Kojirō
질풍노도의 츠바메가에시를 다시 보겠소!
We'll see his stormy Tsubamegaeshi again-dasu!
다음 이야기
어!?
침울한 코지로이오
재미있게 보세요!
Next Story
That's Bad!
Depressed Kojirō
We hope you enjoy!